# Curriculum Vitae Jeremy D. Castagno

646 Old River Cove, Cordova, TN

385-204-6580, JeremyBYU@gmail.com, http://jeremybyu.github.io/aboutme/

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a graduate of Chemical Engineering from Brigham Young University with minors in Computer Science and Mathematics. I recently worked for Valero Energy Corporation as a Process Control Engineer where I provided operation support and assisted capital projects. Prior to this I was an intern for Valero at their San Antonio headquarters analyzing and improving gasoline blending models. While I studied at BYU I worked part time as a Research Assistant for a group called PRISM or Process Research and Intelligent System Modelling (<a href="http://apm.byu.edu/prism">http://apm.byu.edu/prism</a>). My research focused on real time model predictive control and parameter estimation. My area of expertise is modeling physical systems and developing robust control strategies.

### **RELATED EXPERIENCE**

# Valero Energy Corporation, Memphis, TN Process Control Engineer

May 2013- October 2015

Daily control systems support for operation of multiple process units.

Reviewed and verified several safety systems through simulation and creation of detailed test plans. Lead gasoline blending control system upgrade while incorporating advanced process control with an estimated savings of 2 MM/yr.

Systems administrator of workstations, servers, and firewalls for the Process Control Network.

# **Brigham Young University PRISM**, Provo, UT Research Assistant

August 2012- April 2013

Assisted graduate research and publication of Moving Horizon Parameter Estimation (MHE) of UAV's. Developed and implemented real time mixed-integer nonlinear programming control of a laboratory benchmark system utilizing MATLAB.

Programmed an interface (C++) between MATLAB and a laboratory control system while documenting all features clearly.

# Valero Energy Corporation, San Antonio, TX Economics & Process Optimization Intern

April 2012- August 2012

Performed a thorough engineering statistical analysis of corporate gasoline blend models. These models are used in predicting gasoline properties and are executed in planning for several oil refineries. Identified model weaknesses and implemented improvements resulting in a 50% increase in model accuracy.

**Brigham Young University**, Provo, UT **PC Windows Administrator** 

August 2010- August 2012

Managed over 400+ PC's and Servers

Programmed custom scripts and programs for software deployment Assisted in user account creation and maintenance

#### **EDUCATION**

**B.S Chemical Engineering Brigham Young University** 

GPA: 3.73

Minors: Computer Science (GPA: 4.0), Mathematics (GPA: 3.85)

#### PROFESSIONAL SERVICE AND MEMBERSHIPS

International Society of Automaton Member (ISA)

#### **COMMUNITY SERVICE**

Cub Scout Den Leader, Memphis, TN

Led young men on outings, rank advancement, and weekly meetings Taught many lessons assisting character and intellectual development

Sunday School Teacher, Memphis, TN Educated young children in gospel lessons

September 2013 – Current

Study Abroad Engineers Without Borders, Cusco, Peru & Provo, Utah August 2011-May 2012 Organized a multi-discipline engineer team creating low cost water filters. Designed, created, and distributed multiple engineering projects in rural villages.

# Volunteer Representative, India

July 2008 – July 2010

Served as missionary for The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints Coordinated efforts of sixteen representatives as a leader

# **SKILLS**

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

Programming: C, C++, C#, JavaScript, Python, VBA Web development: Meteor, Angular, React, HTML, CSS

Databases: MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server

### **INTERESTS**

Exercise: Running, weightlifting, hiking, kayaking Web Design/Apps: Websites, Android Apps

# **HONORS AND AWARDS**

BYU Alvina Soffel Barrett Scholarship 2011 - 2013 BYU General Engineering Scholarship 2010 - 2011

### PEER REVIEWED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

August 2006-April 2013

September 2013 – May 2015

Sun, L., Castagno, J., Hedengren, J. D., and Beard, R. W., Parameter Estimation for Towed Cable Systems Using Moving Horizon Estimation, IEEE Transactions on Aerospace and Electronic Systems, Vol. 51, No. 2, April 2015.